America and welcome to the new lesson
today i'm going to share some tips that
can help you to create a positive first
impression
now you might have studied that it takes
about only three and five seconds for
someone to form an impression about
somebody
well at times you meet new people and do
you think to yourself that
oh my god this person was a little weird
or she was not at all impressive
and are you afraid that you meeting
someone that person would also take the
same about you
well let these worries that bother you
here are some tips that will help you to
create a good positive first impression
the first that i have for you is to set
an intention
now it is essential for you to set an
intention
especially when you are going to attend
a big wet which means where you know
that you're going to end up meeting some
new people that can be maybe at a
conference or maybe it's some social
gathering or even a friend's party or
even for an interview
these are the places where you
definitely end up meeting new people
so when you're getting ready you getting
dressed up or when you're driving or
traveling to get to the event
make sure that you stay calm and
composed and think what kind of
interactions you would like to have with
these new people that you would meet now
this is important because this will help
you to stay focused and also give you
that positive energy for that kind of an
event that you would be attending
so do set an intention little bit of
heart and some practice would help you
to form a positive and pray
that i have for you is to present
yourself appropriate me now definitely
your physical appearance does matter
because the person that you are meeting
for the first time doesn't have a clue
about you doesn't know anything about
your experience about your intelligence
are about your knowledge all he can see
is your physical appearance and that
would kind of give him an idea about
what kind of person you are
so it is important for you to dress
properly
well if you are attending a business
meeting or if you are attending some
kind of a formal event
make sure you are dressed up in a formal
attire
if you are attending a party or if you
were attending a social gathering
make sure you are dressed appropriately
now this doesn't mean that you have to
look like a model
just perfect grooming and personal
hygiene would also help you
so physical appearance would matter
that's why it's important that you
present yourself appropriately
that i have for you is to be open and
confident now body language does matter
in fact it speaks louder than words so
it is important for you to show
confidence and how would you do that
well you need to smile when you meet
someone for the first time make sure
that you stand tall and project that
kind of confidence and of course make
good eye contact
that's extremely important because if
you are looking somewhere else when you
are meeting someone
it just doesn't show that you are
interested in meeting that new person so
a good eye contact a firm handshake and
smiling would definitely help
this would help you to project
confidence and please do a wide you're
nervous habits we all get nervous
meeting someone for the first time but
do avoided like touching your phase are
biting nails or you know playing around
with your hair or with your phone please
do a white that
so please be confident and this would
help you to create a good impression
to be courteous and attended goes
without saying that good manners and
being polite to someone definitely helps
and helps you to create a very positive
impression on someone
now your new acquaintances definitely
deserve a hundred percent of your
attention
of course when you are meeting someone
be polite
be gentle okay you don't have to sound
very rude and make sure that you let
them know that you are listening to them
and of course you don't start talking
about stories about your collection of
shoes or you start talking that oh my
god how adorable my puppy is ok
these talks would not make any sense so
maybe you can talk about current affairs
you can talk about music you can talk
about new movies
okay make sure whatever you talk has
some sense ok
and of course make sure that you listen
to the other person
last that i would like to share with you
is to close on a good note
now this means you would want the person
wanting for more
how would you do that well show that
you're extremely happy to meet this
person
while say goodbye to this person
you can say oh it was great talking to
you Jane
or you can say it was a pleasure meeting
and with this note you can exchange your
business cards or email addresses or
even your phone numbers
so this would help you to stay in touch
with this person
alright so this brings me to the end of
this lesson
hope these tips are helpful to you and
remember you do not have a second chance
to create the first impression
do follow these tips and it would
definitely help you to create a very
positive and a very last post impression
i will see you soon in the next lesson
until then you take care and have a good